A Guide to the Records of Eastern State Hospital, 1770-2009
Library of Virginia
- Series IV. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1791-1997., Extent: 9.125 cu. ft., 3 volumes. (Box 13-33., Volume 037-039.)
  - Subseries B. Correspondence and Subject Files (Director), 1937-1993., Extent: 4.95 cu. ft. (Box 14-24.)
    - Photo album, unidentified (photocopy), undated. (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Poem: "Don't Shake the Bottle, Shake Your Mother-in-Law," by Phyllis McGinley, undated. (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Polio vaccine, 1963. (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Population trends letter, 1954. (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Portrait unveiling: Dr. George W. Brown, 1941. (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Potential increase in patient housing, Report on, 1954. (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Programs and guest lists (miscellaneous), 1951-1956. (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Proposal for an Integrated Mental Health System for HSA-V, 1985. (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Psychiatric Residency Training Program, 1955-1962. (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Psychiatric Residency Training Program, 1966-1972. (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Psychiatric Residency Training Program, 1977-1982. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Psychiatric Residency Training Program, 1983-1987. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Reasons for immediate admission (notes), undated (circa 1964). (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Reimbursement, 1948-1972. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Reimbursement, 1973-1975. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Reimbursement, 1976-1977. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Reimbursement, 1978-1984. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Reise, Walther, M.D.: List of scientific publications by, undated. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Report on present trends in admissions at Lynchburg Training School and Hospital (submitted to the State Hospital Board), 1960. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Research Department, Establishment of (joint Psy.D. program), 1968-1975. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - "Resume of the Past Two Biennia," 1962-1966. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Retirement of Garland L. Whitmer, 1986-1987. (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Service of Legal Process upon Insane, Mentally Defective, and Epileptic Patients, and the Execution of Instruments by Them (Regulation No. 9), undated. (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Security Department report, 1980. (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Senate Joint Resolution No. 52: Study of the Need for Additional Authority for Criminal Prosecution of Suspected Abuse in Facilities for the Mentally Disabled, 1988. (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Shooting incident, 1990. (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Social Service Department report, 1959. (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Staff development and training: Nursing Assistant Program, 1986. (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Sterilizations: ACLU class-action lawsuit, 1980-1984. (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Stokes, Hugh G., M.D. (Chief of Staff), 1978-1980. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Stokes, Hugh G., M.D. (Chief of Staff), 1981-1982. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Stokes, Hugh G., M.D. (Chief of Staff), 1982-1983. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Stokes, Hugh G., M.D. (Chief of Staff), 1984-1989. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Superintendents' meetings (minutes and rules), 1963-1971. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Supervisor's daily report, 1956. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Surgical Services discontinuation, 1979-1982. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Survey of insurance and record of assets (contains photographs), 1967. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - "Think of Me: Two Centuries of Caring for the Mentally Ill in Williamsburg," (lecture series), 1993. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Token Economy Program, 1969-1976. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Tour: Commissioner and Delegates, 1984-1986. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Tour: Commissioner Cullum and staff, 1989. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Tour: Governor Gerald Baliles, 1988. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Tour: Human Resources Subcommittee, 1987. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Tour: Senate Finance Committee, 1989. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Tours (correspondence), 1979-1990. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Virginia state government: Office of the Governor, 1970-1975. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Virginia state government: Office of the Governor, Executive Orders, 1974-1975. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Virginia state government: Secretary of Human Resources, 1977-1983. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Vocational rehabilitation, 1953-1973. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Vocational rehabilitation, 1974-1981. (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - "What will Eastern State Hospital be like in the year 2000?" (quote by David Pribble), 1990. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Working patients (memoranda), 1971-1978. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Subseries C. Correspondence and Subject Files (Director: Kurt T. Schmidt, M.D.), 1953-1982., Extent: .225 cu. ft. (Box 24-25.)
    Files and miscellaneous items found together during processing that belonged to hospital director, Kurt T. Schmidt, M.D. The material was given its own subseries because it had been separated from the other correspondence and subject files associated with the Office of the Director. Most of the items are personal in nature, except for a small amount of correspondence, an essay, and a speech on the state of the hospital.
    - A Lutheran Prayer Book, edited by John W. Doberstein, 1960. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Certificates, 1953-1971. (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1982. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - "Eastern State Hospital, 25 Years Hence," 1973. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Plaque (service award), undated, circa 1981. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - State of the Hospital address, 1967. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - "The Art of Contemplation," by Alan Watts, 1972. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D. Correspondence, Subject Files and Ledgers (Superintendent), 1791-1937., Extent: 3.5 cu. ft., 3 volumes. (Box 25-33., Volume 037-039.)
    Contains correspondence, miscellaneous files and ledgers created and maintained during the earliest years of the hospital's existence. Material from two accessions (31783 and 44812) were interfiled in this subseries for ease of research. Most of the records can be traced to the era of superintendents Dr. John M. Galt, both father and son. The correspondence is sporadic and mostly patient-related. Many of the letters are from local jailors and sheriffs wishing to place insane inmates. Other letters are from family members inquiring about the status of a particular patient. A few personal letters and letters pertaining to hospital business matters also exist. The files contain draft reports, accounts, bonds, contracts, and essays on mental health topics. Much of this material is in draft form, may be missing pages, or is difficult to read. Final publications of many of the draft essays written by Dr. John M. Galt can be found in Series XV. Publications.
    Correspondence is arranged chronologically and the subject files and ledgers are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Correspondence
      - 1791 (photocopy). (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - 1815. (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - 1832-1840. (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - 1841. (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - 1842. (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - 1843. (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - 1844 January-June. (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - 1844 July-December. (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - 1845. (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - 1846 January-March. (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - 1846 April-June. (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - 1846 July-September. (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - 1846 October-December. (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - 1847 January-July. (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - 1847 August-December. (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - 1848. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - 1849 January-March. (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - 1849 April-May. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - 1849 June-July. (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - 1849 August-December. (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - 1850. (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - 1851. (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - 1852. (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - 1853 January-June. (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - 1853 July-December. (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - 1854 January-April. (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - 1854 May-August. (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - 1854 September-December. (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - 1855 January-June. (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - 1855 July-October. (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - 1855 November-December. (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - 1856 January-May. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - 1856 June-July. (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - 1856 August-September. (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - 1856 October-December. (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - 1857 January-May. (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - 1857 June-July. (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - 1857 August-December. (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - 1858 January-February. (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - 1858 March-May. (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - 1858 June-July. (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - 1858 August-September. (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - 1858 October-December. (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - 1859 January-May. (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - 1859 June-July. (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - 1859 August-December. (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - 1860 January-April. (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - 1860 May-December. (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - 1861 January-June. (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - 1861 July-December. (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - 1862. (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - 1870-1878. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - 1894; 1898. (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - undated. (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - undated. (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - undated. (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - undated. (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - undated. (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Letters to Dr. Francis Stribling (Western Lunatic Asylum superintendent) 1841; 1856; 1873. (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Letters to the Board of Directors from the Superintendent (drafts), 1841-1858; undated. (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Subject Files
      - "A communication to the legislature, respecting the laws and regulating the admission of patients into the Eastern Asylum," undated. (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - "A communication touching the state of the asylum," undated. (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - "A diary" (fragment), undated. (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - "A Song of the South" (poem?), 1861. (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - "A third state lunatic asylum in Virginia" (draft/fragment), undated. (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - Accounts and receipts, 1842-1880. (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Admission and patient statistics (ages, eye/hair color, diagnosis, occupation), 1845-1849; undated. (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - Admission of colored patients, Notes on, undated. (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - Admission of insane slaves, Notes on acts concerning, undated. (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - Admission questionnaire (blank), 1858. (Box 28, Folder 24)
      - Almanac pages (fragments), 1869. (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - "Americans" (poem), 1850. (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - Animal classification, Notes on, undated. (Box 28, Folder 27)
      - "Anniversary Oration," by Alfred C. Posts (cover page only), 1849. (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - Annual report of the directors of the Eastern Asylum to the legislature of Virginia (with report of the superintendent), 1842. (Box 28, Folder 29)
      - Annual reports (1855-1857; 1867-1859; 1859-1861), 1861. (Box 28, Folder 30)
      - Annual reports (drafts/fragments), 1842-1845. (Box 28, Folder 31)
      - Annual reports (drafts/fragments), 1846-1849. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Annual reports (drafts/fragments), 1850-1857; undated. (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Answers to questions in report of Pennsylvania hospital, undated. (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Appendix: "Miscellaneous items relative to the colored insane" (with notes), undated. (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - "Appendix to work on insanity," 1846. (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Appropriations, Statement of, undated. (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Arithmetic, Notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Assistant physician, Notice concerning the appointment of an, 1850. (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Association of Medical Superintendents of American Institutions for the Insane, Circular regarding meeting of, 1846. (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Astronomy, Essay/notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - Authorization to contract for pork, 1846. (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - Biblical quotations, undated. (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - Bibliographies and reading notes (miscellaneous), undated. (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - Bloodletting in insanity, Notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Board members, Lists of (?), 1843-1851. (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Board of Directors meeting invitation and notes, 1847. (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Bonds: Admission of patients, 1852-1877. (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - Bonds: Blank, 1841; 1845; 1849. (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - Bonds: Slave patients, undated. (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - Bonds: Steward's, 1871. (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - Bonds: Storekeeper, 1868-1871. (Box 29, Folder 21)
      - Bonds: Treasurer's, 1868-1872. (Box 29, Folder 22)
      - Books and periodicals, Order to purchase, 1843. (Box 29, Folder 23)
      - Books published by J.S. Redfield, List of (advertisement), undated. (Box 29, Folder 24)
      - Booksellers of political essays, List of, undated. (Box 29, Folder 25)
      - Botany and plants, Notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - Building Committee, Report of the (draft), 1850. (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - Buildings at the gate, Cost estimate for, undated. (Box 29, Folder 28)
      - Carpenter, Notice about the position of, undated. (Box 29, Folder 29)
      - Case histories, 1830-1836; undated. (Box 29, Folder 30)
      - Case histories (fragments), 1813-1837; undated. (Box 29, Folder 31)
      - Case histories (missing pages), 1812-1837; undated. (Box 29, Folder 32)
      - "Cases in Surgery" (fragment), undated. (Box 29, Folder 33)
      - Census of 1840 (statistics on the number of insance by locality), 1840. (Box 29, Folder 34)
      - Changing names of asylums, Notes on, 1861. (Box 29, Folder 35)
      - Cholera, Articles about, undated. (Box 29, Folder 36)
      - Circulars, Order for (also contains a notice regarding the procurement of a teaching position), undated. (Box 29, Folder 37)
      - Clothing, Notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 38)
      - Comets, Essay/notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 39)
      - "Commentaries on the Causes, Forms, Symptoms and Treatment of Insanity," by George Mann Burrows, Notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 40)
      - "Comments on the code of by-laws adopted in the Eastern Lunatic Asylum" (job descriptions), 1857. (Box 29, Folder 41)
      - Commitment papers, 1843-1937; undated. (Box 29, Folder 42)
      - Committee appointed "on asylums for colored people," Report to the Association of Medical Superintendents of American Institutions for the Insane, undated (post-1844). (Box 29, Folder 43)
      - Committee on Lunatic Asylums, Report of (fragment), undated. (Box 29, Folder 44)
      - Communication from Dr. John Galt, Notice regarding (Board of Directors), 1857. (Box 29, Folder 45)
      - "Communication to the Board of Directors of the Eastern Asylum," (draft Superintendent's report), 1843. (Box 29, Folder 46)
      - Cost of board, Notes on the, undated. (Box 29, Folder 47)
      - Court yards, Notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 48)
      - "'Cravius Brittanica:' A New Ethnological Work," Notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 49)
      - Deaf, Dumb and Blind Institution, Report of the Board of Visitors, Doc. 19, 1850. (Box 29, Folder 50)
      - Deaths, discharges and elopements, List of (draft), undated (circa 1859). (Box 29, Folder 51)
      - Deeds, 1869. (Box 29, Folder 52)
      - Diagnosis, Notes on, undated. (Box 29, Folder 53)
      - Disease statistics (fragments), 1812-1837. (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Dislocated joints, Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - District law (hospital boundaries), Notes on undated (circa 1845). (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Division of patients between Western Lunatic Asylum and Eastern Lunatic Asylum, Notes on the, 1841; undated. (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Donations (private), Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Doric building, Ordering regarding use of (for Board of Director's meetings), 1857. (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Dr. Greene's Indianopathy (advertisement), undated. (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Drawing of men on horses (pencil), undated. (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Election of Dr. John Galt as superintendent, Notice regarding (Board of Directors), 1841. (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Employee assignments (?), undated. (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Employees and servants, Lists of, 1844; undated. (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Encyclopedia entries - "Per" (fragment), undated. (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Essay: Untitled fragment (topics: management, classification, amusements, labor and employment), undated. (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - "Essays on Asylums for Persons of Unsound Mind," (First and Second series, with notes), 1850-1853. (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - Executive Committee, Notes on the responsibilities of, undated. (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - Executive Committee, Report to the (superintendent's report), 1847. (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - Famous cases of insanity, Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - Female asylums, Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - Female officer, Notice to appoint a, 1848. (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - Female reproductive organs and childbirth, Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 20)
      - "Fisher's Restraining Apparatus for Insane Persons," Advertisement for, undated. (Box 30, Folder 21)
      - Floorplan, Sketch of (unidentified), undated. (Box 30, Folder 22)
      - Fongera's Ready-made Mustard Plasters, Advertisement for, undated. (Box 30, Folder 23)
      - Forwarding request to the Post Master, undated. (Box 30, Folder 24)
      - Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper (untitled article), 1880. (Box 30, Folder 25)
      - French medical pamphlets (various), undated. (Box 30, Folder 26)
      - Galt, Alexander, Biographical sketch of, undated (circa 1860). (Box 30, Folder 27)
      - Galt, Alexander, Obituary for (draft), undated. (Box 30, Folder 28)
      - Galt, Alexander, Signature of, undated. (Box 30, Folder 29)
      - Galt, Annie, Obituary for, undated. (Box 30, Folder 30)
      - Galt, John M., "An Essay on Botany for the Degree of Doctor of Medicine," University of Pennsylvania, 1841; 1843; undated. (Box 30, Folder 31)
      - Galt, John M., Biographical notes concerning, undated. (Box 30, Folder 32)
      - Galt, John M., Certificates in midwifery and medicine, 1740; 1767. (Box 02)
      - Galt, John M., Graduation certificates, University of Pennsylvania, 1840-1841. (Box 30, Folder 33)
      - Galt, John M., Obituary for, 1862. (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - Galt, John M., Tax receipt, 1848. (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - Galt, Sally (Sallie), Correspondence, 1856-1862; undated. (Box 30, Folder 36)
      - Gas, Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 37)
      - General Assembly, Petition to the, 1845. (Box 30, Folder 38)
      - German expressions (translated), undated. (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Goode, Thomas J., Will of, 1834. (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - "Gray's Elegy" (poem), undated. (Box 30, Folder 41)
      - Guerrant v. Goode, Notes on, 1856. (Box 30, Folder 42)
      - Guide to Health and Long Life, by Robert J. Culverwell, M.D., 1849. (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - Hallucination, Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - Hebrew roots for English words, List of, undated. (Box 30, Folder 45)
      - Hiring of employees and servants, Notice concerning the, undated. (Box 30, Folder 46)
      - Hospital boundaries, Notes on (fragments), undated. (Box 30, Folder 47)
      - Hospital employment, Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 48)
      - Hospitals and asylums, Notes on (possibly drafts of "Essays on Asylums"), undated. (Box 30, Folder 49)
      - Idiots and idiocy, Notes on, 1846; undated. (Box 30, Folder 50)
      - Improvements, Figures for, undated. (Box 30, Folder 51)
      - Improvements, Report on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 52)
      - Improvements to the hospital, Report on (relative to $7000 appropriation), 1853. (Box 30, Folder 53)
      - Incidents, Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 54)
      - Indices and tables of contents (unidentified), undated. (Box 30, Folder 55)
      - "Insanity in Italy" (essay), undated. (Box 30, Folder 56)
      - "Instructions for Observation of the Aurora," (Smithsonian Institution circular), 1849. (Box 30, Folder 57)
      - Instruments used during childbirth, Notes on, undated. (Box 30, Folder 58)
      - "Internal improvements," (essay/notes), undated. (Box 30, Folder 59)
      - Jewett's Advertiser (cover pages), 1840; 1842. (Box 30, Folder 60)
      - Job descriptions, undated. (Box 30, Folder 61)
      - Journal (miscellaneous poetry, writing, etc.), undated. (Box 30, Folder 62)
      - Journal (superintendent's), 1840-1841; undated. (Box 30, Folder 63)
      - Journal entry (fragment), 1859. (Box 30, Folder 64)
      - Journal of legislative notes, undated. (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Keeping of dogs, Resolution regarding the (Court of Directors), 1842. (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Kentucky State Lunatic Asylum, Report on (fragment), undated. (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Kitchen, Contract for, 1847. (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Latin words, List of, undated. (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Law regarding release of harmless patients, Notes on, undated (circa 1850). (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Laws, Notes on, undated (circa 1840-1846). (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Legislation, Notes on (Board of Directors), 1841. (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Legislation, Notes on (miscellaneous), undated. (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - "Legislative acts relative to the insane hospitals in Virginia" (essay), undated. (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - Libraries, Notes on, undated. (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Library of Useful Knowledge publications (electricity, galvanism, electromagnetism), 1827-1831. (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Lithograph prints of hospital, Rough proofs of (north, east and west views), undated. (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - Mailing lists for annual report, 1846-1854. (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - Mailing lists for annual reports, undated. (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - Male reproductive organs, Diagram of, undated. (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Merrimac battle, Notes on the, undated. (Box 31, Folder 17)
      - Moore, Rev. Richard C., Eulogy for, undated. (Box 31, Folder 18)
      - Moral management, Notes on, undated. (Box 31, Folder 19)
      - New building committee, Report of (draft), undated. (Box 31, Folder 20)
      - Newspaper articles (some asylum-related), undated. (Box 31, Folder 21)
      - Notes, Miscellaneous subjects (drafts/fragments), undated. (Box 31, Folder 22)
      - Notes, Miscellaneous subjects (drafts/fragments), undated. (Box 31, Folder 23)
      - "On the Lincoln Asylum" (essay and notes), 1853; undated. (Box 31, Folder 24)
      - "On the propriety of treating the insane and persons affected with other diseases in the same establishment" (report), 1851; undated. (Box 31, Folder 25)
      - "On vassel" and on "Law of nations" (essays/notes), undated. (Box 31, Folder 26)
      - "On water closets" (essay/report), 1850. (Box 31, Folder 27)
      - Opening of a new building and need for a female officer, Notice regarding the, 1849. (Box 31, Folder 28)
      - Patient census, 1773-1853. (Box 31, Folder 29)
      - Patient discharge (draft), undated. (Box 31, Folder 30)
      - Patient letters (?), 1859; undated. (Box 31, Folder 31)
      - Patient pass, undated. (Box 31, Folder 32)
      - Patient statistics, 1856-1862. (Box 31, Folder 33)
      - Patients, Lists of (?), 1842-1857. (Box 31, Folder 34)
      - Patients by locality of origin (no names given), undated. (Box 31, Folder 35)
      - Patients from the Navy and Marine Corps, Order to receive (draft), undated. (Box 31, Folder 36)
      - Patients (male) in hospital, List of, 1841. (Box 31, Folder 37)
      - Patients postponed and rejected, List of, 1856. (Box 31, Folder 38)
      - Pay patients, List of (also contains notes on superstition and insanity), undated. (Box 32, Folder 1)